so let's say you got a spending habit
you know you get paid you're not very
good
at hanging on to your money right
and you're left with this small
accounts you know 100 bucks in here
roughly canadian worth way less american
what do you do how do you grow that
small account how do you flip
that account faster into
a large-ish account so that you can
actually start practicing the normal
forex rules
uh because i know it's very tempting uh
to want to grow that
smaller account very very quickly
because this hundred dollars
probably doesn't mean too too much to
you right away because it is such a
small amount
but once you do get to that ten thousand
dollar mark
then you're going to want to actually
start practicing all of the rules that
i've been talking about in other videos
and i completely understand this
you guys don't necessarily want to be
super risk management
like i do teach normally so let's kind
of dive into
what you would do if you only had a
hundred dollars
and you wanted to grow that into ten
thousand
all right guys so like uh usual everyone
likes
uh three easy tips so i think we're
gonna do that again we're gonna go three
easy tips
on how you're gonna grow your small
account and i will actually
uh make a effort in the future to make a
strategy around small growing a small
account so
make sure that you hit the subscribe
there so that you can jump on that if
you do
have a smaller account you know less
than 10k i would say
it would be a specific strategy maybe
even less than a thousand or something
a specific strategy that i think would
be
most well versed for very small cap
accounts
uh people who need that thing there so
the first thing that i would want to
mention with growing a small account
is you do still want to manage your risk
at least
to some degree in that you have to have
the same amount of risk in each trade
with slight variations depending on the
strategy depending on the setup
but you generally always want to be
following the same
loss per trade usually so
you know for example if you're a new
trader here i assume you are if you have
a new account
uh the pound pairs they actually
move a lot more in pips on average so
a single lot size for every single trade
so let's say you bet
0.02 for every single trade
that you're actually going to lose way
more on the pound pairs when you
actually take a loss so you have to
actually calculate your risk properly
here
so the next thing that we'll we'll need
to note
is that swing trades longer term trades
those are really going to make you lose
more of your account as well
so we're not going to really be able to
take those swing trades because the
lowest amount that you're going to be
able to trade
is 0.01 and we might want to be taking
profits along the way
so i don't even recommend doing a binary
trade like that where it's either you're
in or you're out
you should be able to take profit along
the way if something does arise
so we do need to make sure that we
completely omit
the swing trades so we're going to have
to dive into
a strategy and that will be in a future
video where
we are looking at the lower time frames
and we're looking
at a day trading type thing and we're
looking for the optimal
entry timing and then getting in and out
very quickly because that's going to
allow us to have
a tighter stop and then we're going to
be able to bet higher amounts
because if you only have 100 for example
you're really going to have
a problem because you're going to need
to be betting you know .02
even on these small scalp trades and
that's going to be basically the minimum
that you can do there
the next thing that you can do i really
really strongly always have been
advocating
and i teach people how to actually
calculate their position size
that we want to risk two percent of our
total account
per trade um or one percent if you're
using a larger account over 10k
that's my personal preference and then
when you get even bigger you go even
lower
than that and so this kind of holds true
as well because
in a smaller account what i just said in
the first tip there
is you're going to actually going to be
able to risk more here
so that you can take those profits so i
would never risk more than five percent
and if you guys want to know a formula i
have made some videos on how to
calculate your risk size if you want to
check those out on the channel
and um we're gonna basically be going
and we're gonna be calculating a five
percent loss for every single trade
and then that way you're gonna be able
to grow that small account faster
assuming
that you do have a profitable strategy
now the reason i say five percent as an
absolute maximum
is because it's very easy when you guys
are starting out you can very easily go
on like a 10 loss losing streak and
that's going to basically after
diminishing returns because your
account's getting smaller you're going
to be left with about 60
of your account and that's a major major
uh drawdown for some people's mental
psyche
mind you if you only have a hundred
dollars forty dollar loss might not be a
big deal for you
so that's why you know you can go with
the five percent it's not really a big
deal
but the name of the game guys remember
is you want to keep your capital and you
have to
even think that way when you have a
small account don't
ever be going into things saying okay
we're going to kind of go all or nothing
here
and that's a very very risky way to go
always cut your losers
and then continue with the next trade
and then you just keep going
on until you fully understand things in
the long run it's a very long term game
here
so i'm actually just going to show you
guys quickly on how i'm going to
calculate risk here just in this video
as well
so if we do want to calculate risk let's
say that we wanted to take a short
on this trade for whatever reason we
wanted to go sell
right there we put our stop above there
and then we target wherever we want here
so normally what i would advise is we
would risk two percent of our account
each time
uh but as you have a smaller account you
don't care as much
so we can go as high as five percent and
i think that's perfectly fair
uh for you guys who just want to grow a
little bit faster you want a little bit
more excitement because nobody really
cares about losing
you know uh two dollars per trade
something like that it's not really a
big deal five dollars maybe
uh it's a little bit more of a deal it
really depends on who you are
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
pull up our calculator tool here
and the very easiest formula or you can
use a tool that calculates
for you this is just very easy for me
what we do is we place our tool down
there
our position tool and then we say a
hundred dollars which is our account
size
and then we times it by how much we want
to risk so we want to risk five percent
right so 500
is how much we're able to uh use and
then we're going to
divide that by the percent distance the
stop so you see right there
0.45 0.45 so we divide that sorry
uh we'll have to clear that 500 divided
by 0.45
is gonna give us this number here right
so
you can see that this is kind of a funky
number what we have to do is this is a
us dollar value we have to convert this
to lots and one lot is a hundred
thousand dollars if you guys know this
already
so we have to divide that by a hundred
thousand dollars and that's going to
give us how much we need to bet
per for our trade to work so you can
really understand what i'm talking about
here is if you only have a 100
account and you make a trade like this
which is a relatively low
time frame it's a 15 minute and it's not
a very dis
distant stop is it that's probably the
widest stop that you could handle
and it's still going to be a 0.01 lot
size
so that means you have to let it run to
the very end
so in a case like this i would actually
be wanting to take
profits earlier if i do have a binary
if i have a 0.01 trade because i don't
think i'm going to be able to get to the
very end maybe
my first take profit might have been
around here my second take profit would
have been around here
so i'm going to look to get off maybe
somewhere in the middle maybe a strong
resistance area
and i'm going to have to take a shorter
risk reward trade
than i normally would because i'd want
to make sure i lock in those profits
the other thing that you could do is you
could move your stop forward
and then you can secure the profits that
way now i've just made a video on how to
manage your stops so hopefully
you can check that out i'll put a
reminder up here of the eye there so
you guys can see it if i do remember if
not you'll have to search for it
yourself
so the final thing that i do need to say
actually and it's kind of obvious
when i do say it but you know it doesn't
really matter if you have a small
account or a big account
and the thing is most important about
trading is you have to find a profitable
strategy
and i do talk about this so much on my
channel
how you're going to create data how
you're going to back test things there's
back testing videos you search my
channel you want
you have to find and prove a strategy is
profitable
before you even go into trading so you
have to figure out
different ideas you're going gonna have
to scroll back you're gonna have to back
test them and see
if the logic of the idea does actually
in turn make money after you've tested
so many sample sizes
25 data points 50 data points things
like this and if you don't have a
profitable strategy then there's no
point to even be trading because
you're just gambling at that point in
the very end of the day
again guys i am going to actually dive
into a strategy
on how to trade with a small
account size so we're going to actually
figure out a quick
strategy i'm going to show it to you
it's going to be a variation of how i
trade most likely
so that you guys can most easily as
beginners with small account size
make it very very simple for you guys
and then you can actually make money i
think
this strategy should work quite well for
you so please make sure you hit that
subscribe button
and if you like this video please make
sure you hit the like and
uh s something else
[Music]
oh
you